STEPHANE KARIM

SOFTWARE ENGINEER/CODER

347 498 5032-<u>stephan.karim.sk@gmail.com</u>-Address: Brooklyn, NY 11233-<u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephane-karim/-StephtheITSloth (github.com)</u>

PROFILE

I am a software engineer with a background in Biology. My experience in Management, Finance, and Customer Service allows me to collaborate and work effectively in a team. I am a creative person with a flair in Photography, and the urge to help people with the power of codes.

SKILLS

Coding Languages

Front End & Styling

Python, React JS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Grid, Flexbox, React Styled-Components

Backend

PostgreSQL, Django, MongoDB, Express, Node, NPM, API, Fetch, Axios

Computer Science

Data Structures, Time & Space Complexity Computer Networking & Security Window & MacOS Operating System

Bilingual

English & French

CAREER SUMMARY

Insurance Agent

National Income | January 2021 to present

 Provide tailored options for Life, health insurance to potential policy holders.

Bartender

Sea Witch | August 2019 to Present

 Enhanced patrons experience by providing courtesy, service, and prioritizing on building positive relationship.

Volunteer

Patient Care | March 2019 to August 2019

• New York-Presbyterian Brooklyn Methodist Hospital Assisted on the Rehab and Psychiatric floor.

Assistant in Chemistry Research | 2016

Quantum Computing Research

Design Chemical structures that optimize quantum computers.

PROJECT

Flashcard Game

https://stephtheitsloth.github.io/Flashcards-How-To-Tricks/

- HTML, Flexbox, Vanilla JavaScript
- Flashcard was a solo project. I was trying to provide novice software engineers like me the opportunity to practice in a game setting. One of the biggest hurdles was to make the card flip dynamically.

Anime For Each (With a 3rd party API)

https://animeforeach.herokuapp.com/search

- React.JS, React Hooks, Grid, Flexbox, Heroku, GitHub, API
- Another solo project, and something that I will enjoy a lot. It is an
 anime website that provides a search field in which you can type any
 anime title, and get back a list of anime. The request is made to a
 third party API.

Deep Dive (Music Review App -- A team effort)

https://music-review-frontend.herokuapp.com/

- React/JavaScript/MongoDB/Express/React Styled-Components
- I was responsible for styling the entire website. It was a challenge that I wanted to take. It was really challenging to work in a team setting. I have learned so much.

Ivorian-Ent (Business look-up-- styling in progress)

https://git.heroku.com/ivorian225-ent.git(front end repo) https://git.heroku.com/pacific-dusk-53111.git(backend API)

- React/Python/PostgreSQL/Django Rest
- I attempted to create a look up landing page for businesses based in the Ivory Coast. Authentication is working, but I wasn't able to finish up the project.

EDUCATIONAL TRAINING

General Assembly

Software Engineer Bootcamp April 2021:

Front End Development, Full-Stack Development, Front-End, Frameworks, APIs and Full-Stack Development

Coursera

IT Support Specialist GOOGLE CERTIFICATE Certificate Expected in June 2021:

Computer Networking, Operating System, System Administration and IT Infrastructure Services, IT Security

CUNY Brooklyn College

Bachelor in Biology Degree expected in December 2021: Member of the National Society of Leaderships and Success, Member of the Pre-Physician Assistant Society.